let's look at the solution to a
write-back cache quiz when we have read
a we're going to check the tag and the
valid bit the tag matches a but the
valid bit is zero so this is a Miss so
now we had one miss we will make the
valid bit be one the tag becomes a this
is a read so the dirty bit is zero note
that the fact that the dirty bit was one
doesn't matter here because this was not
valid so simply it doesn't matter what's
here
if valid bit is zero for that line next
we read B we check the tag and the valid
bit the tag is a mismatch so this is a
Miss we have a Miss we need to kick out
a four that we check the dirty bit it's
zero so we don't have a right back we
replace a with B here the valid bit is 1
the dirty bit is zero because this is a
read next we have a right to be check
the tag and the valid bit this is a hit
so it's not a miss because this is a
right we set the dirty bit next we read
C check the tag mismatch this is a mess
we need to replace B so we check is it
dirty yes it is we need to write back B
to memory then we can bring in C set its
valid bit to 1 and because this is a
read the dirty bit becomes zero
next we read D it's a Miss we need to
kick out C C is clean so we don't have a
right back
we just bring in the an override C in
the cache
it's a read so the dirty bit is zero and
the valid bit is 1 because the tag is
valid next we have a right to D it's a
hit but the dirty bit changes to 1 so
overall we had one right back and for
misses and the state of the cache is
that valid bit is 1 the dirty bit is 1
and the tag corresponds to D